Register of the Joseph Hansen Papers, 1887-1980.
Hoover Institution Archives
- FOURTH INTERNATIONAL FILE, 1930-1980
  - General (material not classifiable under any single country)
    - General
      - Correspondence
        - 1973-1976. Includes letters by Jack Barnes, Pierre Frank, Gus Horowitz, Caroline Lund, Ernest and Gisela Mandel, and Mary-Alice Waters (Folder 7)
        - 1977-1978. Includes letters by Jack Barnes, David Keil, Caroline Lund, Ernest and Gisela Mandel, Alan Wald, and Tim Wohlforth (Folder 8)
      - Writings
        - Camejo, Peter. Reports from Latin America, 1970-1972 (Folder 9)
        - Frank, Pierre
          - General, 1955-1969 (Folder 10)
          - Une Revision du Trotskysme: A Propos de la Rupture de Pablo avec la IVe Internationale, 1966 (Folder 11)
        - Maitan, Livio
          - 1955-1970 (Box 72, Folder 1)
          - 1971-1978 (Folder 2)
        - Mandel, Ernest
          - 1953-1969 (Folder 3)
          - 1970-1976. Includes some biographical information on Mandel (Folder 4)
        - Myers, Allen. Reports on trip to Asia and the Pacific region, 1969-1970 (Folder 5)
        - Pablo, Michel
          - 1952-1955 (Folder 6)
          - 1958-1973. Includes some biographical information on Pablo (Folder 7)
        - Peng, Shu-tse, 1955-1961 (Folder 8)
        - Syvriotis, Barbara. Report on international conference held by National Caucus of Labor Committees (U.S.), International Socialists (U.S.), Lutte Ouvriere (France), International Socialism (Great Britain), and other groups, 1971 (Folder 9)
    - Bolshevik Tendency. Correspondence, declaration, memorandum, other internal documents, and articles, 1976-1977. Includes letter by Nahuel Moreno (Folder 10)
    - International Committee
      - General
        - 1953-1961. Resolutions, report, and other internal documents. Includes writing by Tim Wohlforth (Box 73, Folder 1)
        - 1962-1963. Minutes, resolutions, statements, and other internal documents. Includes writings by Ross Dowson, Gerry Healy, and Cliff Slaughter (Folder 2)
      - Informations Internationales. New series, No. 1, 3, ca. 1962 (Folder 3)
      - International Bulletin
        - No. 6-7, 9-10, 1961-1962 (Folder 4)
        - No. 11-14, 1962-1963 (Folder 5)
      - International Correspondence
        - No. 1-9, 1967 (Folder 6)
        - No. 10-19, 1967-1968 (Folder 7)
    - International Secretariat
      - General. Resolutions, declarations, manifesto, and other internal documents, 1946-1962. Includes writings by George Breitman and Morris Stein (Folder 8)
      - Bulletin d'Information, No. 1, 8, 1961-1962 (Folder 9)
      - Bulletin Interieur, 1947-1962. Includes Vol. II No. 18 (1947); No. 2, 7 (1954-1955); No. [1]-2, 7, 13-14, 17, 23 (1961-1962) (Folder 10)
      - Cuarta Internacional. Ano I No. 1-2, 1963 (Folder 11)
      - Fourth International, 1955-1962. Includes Vol. I No. 3-4 (1955-1956); No. 15 (1962) (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - Information Bulletin, 1958-1962. Includes Vol. I No. 4, [18]-21, 24 (1958-1959); No. 4 (1959); Vol. II No. 4-5 (1959); No. 2-7 (1962) (Folder 2)
      - Internal Bulletin, 1959-1962. Includes No. 1 (1959); n.n. (1960); No. 6 (1961); n.n. (1962); No. 2 (1962); n.n. (1962); No. 8, 10-12, 14 (1962) (Folder 3)
      - Internationalist, 1959-1960. Includes n.n. (1959); Vol. III No. 5 (1960); Vol. IV No. 2, 6, 14 (1960) (Folder 4)
      - Publicaciones: Boletin con Articulos y Documentos de los Periodicos de la IV Internacional en Europa, Ano II No. 60, 1962 (Folder 5)
      - Quatrieme Internationale, 1949-1953. Includes n.n. (1949); n.n. (1953) (Folder 6)
      - Statutes, 1948 (Folder 7)
      - Weekly Labor Bulletin (typescript bulletin issued by Ernest Mandel), 1945 (Folder 8)
    - Leninist-Trotskyist Faction. Resolution and statement, 1977 (Folder 9)
    - Organizing Committee for Reconstruction of the Fourth International
      - General. Pamphlet, leaflets, and internal documents
        - 1971-1973 (Folder 10)
        - 1974-1975 (Folder 11)
      - Bulletin Interieur, No. 1, 1977 (Folder 12)
      - Correspondance Internationale
        - No. 1, 4/5, 7, 1971-1973 (Folder 13)
        - No. 8-10, 1973-1974 (Folder 14)
      - Relations with United Secretariat. Correspondence, memoranda, and statements, 1974-1977. Includes letters by Pierre Lambert and Mary-Alice Waters (Folder 15)
    - Parity Committee (International Committee and International Secretariat). Minutes and communique, 1962-1963 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Revolutionary Marxist Tendency
      - General. Resolutions, declaration, and pamphlets, 1964-1972. Includes writing by Michel Pablo (Folder 2)
      - Bulletin Interieur/Documents, 1964-1965. Includes No. 1-3 (1964); n.n. (1964); No. 6, 9 (1964-1965) (Folder 3)
      - Correspondance Internationale, No. 9-10, 1966 (Folder 4)
      - Internal Bulletin/Documents, 1964-1965. Includes No. 1-4 (1964); n.n. (1964); n.n. (1965) (Folder 5)
      - International Marxist Review, No. 1, 1971 (Folder 6)
      - Relations with United Secretariat. Correspondence, 1964-1979. Includes letters by Jean-Pierre Beauvais and Michel Pablo (Folder 7)
    - Secretariado Latinoamericano del Trotskismo Ortodoxo. Congress document, 1958 (Folder 8)
    - United Secretariat
      - General. Resolutions, statements, and other internal documents, 1964-1976. Includes writings by Fernand Charlier and Ernest Mandel (Folder 9)
      - Bulletin Interieur, 1964-1969. Includes n.n. (1964); No. 7, 15 (1968-1969) (Folder 10)
      - Intercontinental Press file. Includes message by Peng Shu-tse and Ch'en Pi-lan to anniversary banquet; library journal listing and review; and miscellaneous financial and subscription records, 1965-1977 (Folder 11)
      - Internal Bulletin, 1964-1968. Includes Vol. II No. 5 (1964); No. 2-3, 9 (1968) (Folder 12)
      - Minutes, 1965-1974 (incomplete) (Folder 13)
      - Statutes, 1965-1970 (Folder 14)
  - Albania. Printed Party of Labor characterization of Trotskyism, 1966 (Folder 15)
  - Algeria
    - General. Correspondence, clippings, and pamphlet, 1962-1965. Includes letters by Farrell Dobbs and Art Sharon (Folder 16)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-Algerian. Resolutions, reports, statement, and other internal documents, 1957-1976. Includes report by Michel Pablo (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Angola. Resolutions, memoranda, and leaflet, 1975-1976. Includes writings by C. Gabriel and Tony Thomas (Folder 2)
  - Argentina
    - Correspondence
      - 1946-1973. Includes letters by Peter Camejo, Farrell Dobbs, Nahuel Moreno, John Riddell, Ed Shaw, and Horacio Valencia (Folder 3)
      - 1974-1977. Includes letters by Robert J. Alexander, Caroline Lund, Ernest Mandel, D. Marcelo, Nahuel Moreno, Ed Shaw, and Mary-Alice Waters (Folder 4)
    - Fourth International issuances, Argentine
      - Internal
        - General. Internal bulletins, resolutions, memoranda, and other documents. Includes writings by Nahuel Moreno
          - 1941-1973 (Folder 5)
          - 1974-1977 (Folder 6)
          - Undated (Folder 7)
        - "La Logica Marxista," n.d. (Folder 8)
      - Public. Serial issues, pamphlets, and leaflets
        - 1940-1959 (Folder 9)
        - 1971-1972 (Folder 10)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-Argentine. Statements and memoranda, 1969-1976. Includes writings by Peter Camejo and Livio Maitan (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Non-Fourth International issuances. Clippings and printed articles, 1941-1976 (Folder 2)
  - Australia. Correspondence and report, 1946-1973. Includes letters by Ivan Dixon, Bob Gould, Gus Horowitz, John Riddell, and Art Sharon, and report by Keith Locke (Folder 3)
  - Austria. Report, 1946 (Folder 4)
  - Bangladesh. Statement and pamphlet, 1971 (Folder 5)
  - Belgium
    - Correspondence, 1961-1977. Includes letters by Jack Barnes, Caroline Lund, Ernest and Gisela Mandel, Francois Massion, and Barry Sheppard (Folder 6)
    - Fourth International issuances, Belgian. Internal bulletins, statements, articles, and leaflets, 1935-1978. Includes writings by Ernest Mandel and Georges Vereecken (Folder 7)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-Belgian. Report, pamphlets, and articles, 1961-1969. Includes writings by Tom Kemp (Folder 8)
    - Non-Fourth International issuances. Articles from Belgian Communist Party press, 1966 (Folder 9)
  - Bolivia
    - Correspondence, 1952-1972. Includes letters by Farrell Dobbs, Hugo Gonzalez Moscoso, Livio Maitan, George Novack, and Michel Pablo (Folder 10)
    - Fourth International issuances, Bolivian. Resolutions, statements, and other internal documents, 1952-1973. Includes writings by Hugo Gonzalez Moscoso and Guillermo Lora (Folder 11)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-Bolivian. Memoranda, other internal documents, articles, and leaflets, 1943-1972. Includes writing by Luis Vitale (Folder 12)
  - Brazil. Correspondence, resolutions, memoranda, other internal documents, serial issues, and pamphlet, 1935-1976. Includes letters by Timothy Harding and Ernest Mandel (Folder 13)
  - Canada
    - Correspondence
      - 1940-1969. Includes letters by Paul Anderson, Jack Barnes, Earle Birney, Farrell Dobbs, Ross Dowson, George Nasir, John Riddell, Art Sharon, Ed Shaw, and Morris Stein (Folder 14)
      - 1970-1976. Includes letters by Alain Beiner, Ross Dowson, Gus Horowitz, Ernest Mandel, John Riddell, John Steele, and Art Young (Folder 15)
    - Fourth International issuances, Canadian
      - General. Resolutions, minutes, report, speech, and serial issue, 1940-1974. Includes writings by Ross Dowson, George Nasir, and John Riddell (Folder 16)
      - Liaison Committee for Reconstruction of the Fourth International in Canada internal bulletin, 1975 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Non-Fourth International issuances. Clippings, and Communist Party of Canada circular re Trotskyism, 1951-1977 (Folder 2)
  - Chile
    - General. Correspondence, statements, and memoranda, 1946-1977. Includes letters by Peter Camejo, Farrell Dobbs, Caroline Lund, Livio Maitan, Juan Perez, Ed Shaw, Humberto Valenzuela, and Luis Vitale, and memoranda by Pierre Frank and Richard Garza (Folder 3)
    - Fourth International issuances, Chilean. Resolutions, other internal documents, and articles, 1945-1977. Includes writings by Juan Perez, Humberto Valenzuela, and Luis Vitale (Folder 4)
  - China
    - Correspondence
      - 1931-1965. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Ch'en Pi-lan, Farrell Dobbs, Ross Dowson, Pierre Frank, C. Frank Glass, Gerry Healy, Harold R. Isaacs, George Novack, Michel Pablo, Peng Shu-tse, Dan Roberts, Arne Swabeck, and George and Connie Weissman (Folder 5)
      - 1966-1969. Includes letters by Ch'en Pi-lan, Jan Garrett, Ernest Mandel, Peng Shu-tse, Art Sharon, Barry Sheppard, and Wang Fan-hsi (Folder 6)
      - 1970-1978. Includes letters by Jack Barnes, Ch'en Pi-lan, C. Frank Glass, Gus Horowitz, Harold R. Isaacs, Joseph T. Miller, Peng Shu-tse, Yohichi Sakai, Wang Fan-hsi, and Mary-Alice Waters (Folder 7)
    - Fourth International issuances, Chinese
      - General. Resolutions, other internal documents, and articles, 1936-1977. Includes writings by Ch'en Pi-lan, Li On, Peng Shu-tse, and Wang Fan-hsi (Folder 8)
      - Niel-sih, "Five Years of the Left Opposition in China: An Attempt to Explain Its Failure to Make Progress," 1934 (Folder 9)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-Chinese
      - 1930-1965. Resolutions, other internal documents, articles, and pamphlet. Includes writings by C. Frank Glass, Livio Maitan, Dan Roberts, Max Shachtman, and Myra Tanner Weiss (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - 1966-1967. Resolutions, reports, and articles. Includes writings by David Fender, Pierre Frank, Livio Maitan, Ernest Mandel, and Johannes Ernst Seiffert (Folder 2)
      - 1968-1972. Resolutions, other internal documents, and articles. Includes writings by Fernand Charlier, Livio Maitan, Kyoji Nishi, and George Novack (Folder 3)
    - Non-Fourth International issuances. Clippings, other printed matter, and seminar papers, 1956-1977. Includes papers by Joseph T. Miller and Abie Weisfeld (Folder 4)
  - Colombia
    - Correspondence, 1971-1978. Includes letters by Ernest Mandel, Nahuel Moreno, J. P. Riel, Carlos Rodriguez, and Ed Shaw (Folder 5)
    - Fourth International issuances, Colombian. Internal bulletins, reports, resolutions, and other internal documents, 1971-1978. Includes writings by Greco and J. P. Riel (Folder 6)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-Colombian. Resolution and statements, 1977 (Folder 7)
  - Costa Rica
    - Correspondence, 1972-1978. Includes letters by Jack Barnes, Rogelio Cedeno, Caroline Lund, Livio Maitan, Rodrigo, Ed Shaw, and Marta Trejos (Folder 8)
    - Fourth International issuances, Costa Rican
      - General. Reports, other internal documents, and articles, 1977-1978 (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - "Las Premisas Teoricas Fundamentales a la Construccion del Partido Revolucionario," n.d. (Folder 2)
    - Fourth International United Secretariat special commission to investigate charges against Fausto Amador, 1976
      - Exhibits (Folder 3)
      - Reports and resolutions (Folder 4)
    - Non-Fourth International issuances. Clippings, 1969-1978 (Folder 5)
  - Cuba
    - Correspondence, 1960-1978. Includes letters by Pierre Broue, Daniel Camejo, Peter Camejo, Farrell Dobbs, Ross Dowson, Pierre Frank, David Keil, Ernest Mandel, George Nasir, Vernel Olson, and Ed Shaw (Folder 6)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-Cuban. Resolutions, reports, memoranda, other internal documents, and articles, 1960-1975. Includes writings by Ken Coates, Richard Garza, Livio Maitan, Ernest Mandel, Vernel Olson, Peng Shu-tse, Alfonso Ramirez, and Luis Vitale (Folder 7)
    - Non-Fourth International issuances. Printed articles, clippings, and leaflets, 1960-1965. Includes articles on Trotskyism from official Cuban press (Folder 8)
  - Cyprus. Declarations and articles, 1964-1970 (Folder 9)
  - Czechoslovakia. Correspondence, declarations, internal documents, and articles, 1938-1977. Includes letters by Ken Coates and Jiri Pelikan, and writings by Sirio di Giuliomaria and Morris Stein (Folder 10)
  - Denmark. Correspondence and internal documents, 1972-1973. Includes letters by Peter Camejo and Ernest Mandel (Folder 11)
  - Dominican Republic. Correspondence, program, and serial issue, 1963-1972. Includes letters by Peter Camejo and Alberto Malagon (Folder 12)
  - Ecuador. Letter and addresses, 1973-1977 (Folder 13)
  - Eritrea. Letter, 1972 (Folder 14)
  - Finland. Letter and article, 1940-1963 (Folder 15)
  - France
    - Correspondence, 1946-1978. Includes letters by Jack Barnes, Jean-Pierre Beauvais, Marguerite Bonnet, George Breitman, Pierre Broue, Daniel Camejo, Farrell Dobbs, Becky Finch, Pierre Frank, Daniel Guerin, Fred Halstead, Gus Horowitz, David Keil, Alain Krivine, Pierre Lambert, Michel Lequenne, Caroline Lund, Ernest and Gisela Mandel, Felix Morrow, George Novack, Evelyn Reed, Ed Shaw, Barry Sheppard, and Mary-Alice Waters (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Fourth International issuances, French
      - General
        - Internal. Resolutions, and other internal documents, 1953-1975. Includes writings by Lily Cadart, Pierre Frank, and Michele Mestre (Folder 2)
        - Public. Serial issues
          - 1932-1956 (Folder 3)
          - 1966-1968 (Folder 4)
      - Centre d'Etudes Socialistes. Bibliographies, 1968-1969 (Folder 5)
      - Institut Leon Trotsky. Report, statutes, and serial issues, 1977-1978 (Folder 6)
      - Ligue Communiste/Ligue Communiste Revolutionnaire
        - 1969-1970. Internal bulletins, other internal documents, leaflets, and serial issues (Folder 7)
        - 1971-1976. Internal bulletin, other internal documents, and articles. Includes writings by Pierre Frank and Alain Krivine (Folder 8)
      - Organisation Communiste Internationaliste
        - General
          - 1967-1974. Statements, pamphlets, and serial issues (Folder 9)
          - 1975-1976. Congress documents, serial issue, article, and leaflet (Folder 10)
        - Etudes et Documents
          - 1961 (Folder 11)
          - 1967 (Folder 12)
      - Parti Communiste Internationaliste. Internal bulletins, pamphlets, serial issues, and leaflets
        - 1947-1953 (Box 82, Folder 1)
        - 1954-1968 (Folder 2)
      - Parti Communiste Revolutionnaire (Trotskiste). Serial issues, 1966-1967 (Folder 3)
      - Parti Ouvrier Internationaliste. Internal bulletin and serial issue, 1937-1943 (Folder 4)
      - Voix Ouvriere (Organization). Serial issues and leaflet, 1966-1967 (Folder 5)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-French. Reports, resolutions, statements, other internal documents, pamphlets, and articles, ca. 1936-1975. Includes writings by Peter Camejo, Ted Grant, Tom Kemp, John Riddell, and Barry Sheppard (Folder 6)
    - Non-Fourth International issuances. Pamphlet by Yvan Craipeau, and clippings, 1967-1971 (Folder 7)
  - Germany. Correspondence, declaration, memoranda, and articles. Includes letters by Anton Grylewicz, Georg Jungclas, Gisela Mandel, and John Riddell, and writing by Sam Gordon (Folder 8)
  - Great Britain
    - Correspondence
      - 1946. Includes letters by Ted Grant, Gerry Healy, Felix Morrow, and Morris Stein (Folder 9)
      - 1953. Includes letters by Farrell Dobbs, Gerry Healy, and Ernest Mandel (Folder 10)
      - 1954. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Sam Gordon, Gerry Healy, and Louis Sinclair (Folder 11)
      - 1955. Includes letters by George Breitman, Farrell Dobbs, and Gerry Healy (Folder 12)
      - 1956. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Gerry Healy, and Tom Kerry (Folder 13)
      - 1957. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Isaac Deutscher, Farrell Dobbs, Peter Fryer, Gerry Healy, and Tom Kerry (Folder 14)
      - 1958. Includes letters by Farrell Dobbs, Gerry Healy, Tom Kerry, Louis Sinclair, and Geoffrey White (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 1959. Includes letters by Brian Behan, Peter Cadogan, James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Peter Fryer, Gerry Healy, and Dan Roberts (Folder 2)
      - 1960. Includes letters by Brian Behan, Peter Cadogan, James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Milton and Tybie Genecin, Gerry Healy, Tom Kerry, George Novack, Michel Pablo, Evelyn Reed, Louis Sinclair, and Cliff Slaughter (Folder 3)
      - 1961. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Ross Dowson, Milton Genecin, Sam Gordon, Gerry Healy, Walter Kendall, Tom Kerry, Ernest Mandel, and Peng Shu-tse (Folder 4)
      - 1962. Includes letters by Farrell Dobbs, Ross Dowson, Gerry Healy, Tom Kerry, George Novack, and Cliff Slaughter (Folder 5)
      - 1963. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Alan Harris, Gerry Healy, Ernest Mandel, and George Novack (Folder 6)
      - 1964-1965. Includes letters by Michael Banda, J. Brannigan, Daniel Camejo, Farrell Dobbs, Isaac Deutscher, Pierre Frank, Sam Gordon, Alan and Connie Harris, Gerry Healy, Pat Jordan, Ernest Mandel, Ernest Tate, and Connie Weissman (Folder 7)
      - 1966. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Gerry Healy, Ralph Schoenman, Ken Tarbuck, and Ernest Tate (Folder 8)
      - 1967. Includes letters by Tamara Deutscher, Farrell Dobbs, Bob Purdie, Art Sharon, Ed Shaw, and Ernest Tate (Folder 9)
      - 1968-1969. Includes letters by Jack Barnes, Tamara Deutscher, Connie Harris, Caroline Lund, George Novack, Peter Peterson, Art Sharon, Barry Sheppard, and Ernest Tate (Folder 10)
      - 1970. Includes letters by Jack Barnes, Alan and Connie Harris, Gerry Healy, Pat Jordan, Caroline Lund, Peng Shu-tse, Barry Sheppard, and John and Sheila Steele (Folder 11)
      - 1971-1974. Includes letters by Tariq Ali, John Benson, Sam Gordon, Ted Harding, Connie Harris, Gus Horowitz, Alan Jones, Pat Jordan, Ernest Mandel, John Riddell, and George Shriver (Folder 12)
      - 1975. Includes letters by Robin Blick, Sam Gordon, John Lister, Harold Robins, and Tim Wohlforth (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - 1976
        - January-May. Includes letters by Jack Barnes, George Breitman, Sam Gordon, John Lister, Caroline Lund, Alan Jones, George Shriver, Alan Thornett, Adam Westoby, and Tim Wohlforth (Folder 2)
        - June-July. Includes letters by Manuel Aguilar, Ken Coates, Farrell Dobbs, Raya Dunayevskaya, Gerry Foley, Milton Genecin, Albert Glotzer, C. L. R. James, Alan Jones, Caroline Lund, Nahuel Moreno, Chris Moustakis, Jim Percy, Vanessa Redgrave, John Riddell, James Robertson, Barry Sheppard, George Shriver, Bala Tampoe, Luis Vitale, George Weissman, and Tim Wohlforth (Folder 3)
        - August-December. Includes letters by John Archer, Jack Barnes, John Benson, Ken Coates, Milton Genecin, Albert Glotzer, C. L. R. James, Alan Jones, Vanessa Redgrave, Cliff Slaughter, Charles van Gelderen, Jean van Heijenoort, and Tim Wohlforth (Folder 4)
      - 1977-1979. Includes letters by John Archer, Michael Banda, Robin Blick, Ken Coates, Sam Gordon, Alan Jones, John Lister, Michel Pablo, Barry Sheppard, Cliff Slaughter, Ken Tarbuck, Jack Weber, and Tim Wohlforth (Folder 5)
    - Fourth International issuances, British
      - General. Internal bulletins, other internal documents, serial issues, pamphlets, and leaflets
        - 1960-1967 (Folder 6)
        - 1970-1976 (Folder 7)
      - International Bulletin/Bulletin
        - 1962 (Folder 8)
        - 1963 (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - International Marxist Group. Includes Spartacus League material
        - Internal. Internal bulletins, resolutions, memoranda, reports, minutes, and other internal documents
          - 1966-1970. Includes writings by Alan and Connie Harris (Folder 2)
          - 1971-1977. Includes writing by Alan Jones (Folder 3)
        - Public. Serial issues, pamphlet, and leaflets, 1968-1972 (Folder 4)
      - International Tendency. Resolutions, bulletins, statements, reports, and minutes, 1960-1965 (Folder 5)
      - Left Fraction. Bulletins, 1963-1965 (Folder 6)
      - Revolutionary Communist Party
        - Internal. Internal bulletins, resolutions, reports, statements, conference documents, and other internal documents
          - 1944-1945 (Folder 7)
          - 1946-1947 (Folder 8)
          - 1948. Includes writing by Tony Cliff (Box 86, Folder 1)
          - 1949-1950. Includes writings by Tony Cliff and Ted Grant (Folder 2)
        - Public. Workers International News
          - 1944-1947 (Folder 3)
          - 1948-1949 (Folder 4)
      - Revolutionary Socialist League/Militant Group
        - Internal. Internal bulletins, resolutions, minutes, and other internal documents
          - 1950-1964 (Folder 5)
          - 1965-1970. Includes writing by Ted Grant (Folder 6)
        - Public
          - General. Serial issues, pamphlets, and leaflets, 1957-1970. Includes writings by Ted Grant (Folder 7)
          - Socialist Fight, 1961-1963 (Folder 8)
      - Socialist Labour League/Workers Revolutionary Party. See also Great Britain/Socialist Labour League/Workers Revolutionary Party subject file
        - Internal. Internal bulletins, resolutions, statements, reports, minutes, and other internal documents
          - 1953-1958 (Folder 9)
          - 1959-1960. Includes writings by Peter Cadogan (Box 87, Folder 1)
          - 1961-1962. Includes internal bulletin, Relations between the Socialist Workers' Party (USA) and the Socialist Labour League (Britain) (Folder 2)
          - 1962-1970 (Folder 3)
        - Public. Serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, and catalogs of publications
          - 1950-1968. Includes writings by Gerry Healy, William Hunter, Michael Nolan, and Pat Sirockin (Folder 4)
          - 1970-1978. Includes writing by Michael Banda (Folder 5)
      - Workers International League
        - General. Statement on expulsion of Gerry Healy, and issues of Workers International News, 1942-1944 (Folder 6)
        - Socialist Appeal, 1941-1943 (Folder 7)